Guide to the Letters to Francis Vielé-Griffin
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Letters to Francis Vielé-Griffin
1888-1931
GEN MSS 127
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.2
(1 box)
Letters from various people, including Jethro Bithell, Virginia M. Crawford, Osman Edwards, Horace Edwin Hayden, Richard Hovey, T. B. Rudmose-Brown, and Charles Tuckerman, among others.
Vielé-Griffin, Francis, 1864-1937
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased on the Plain Fund, 1940.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
This finding aid encompasses accessions of materials pertaining to Francis Vielé-Griffin.
Poets, French; Bithell, Jethro, 1878-1962; Crawford, Virginia M(Virginia Mary), b. 1862?; Edwards, Osman, 1864-1936; Hayden, Horace Edwin, 1837-1917; Hovey, Richard, 1864-1900; Rudmose-Brown, T. B. (Thomas Brown), 1878-1942; Tuckerman, Charles K. (Charles Keating), 1821-1896; Vielé-Griffin, Francis, 1864-1937
- Letters to Francis Vielé-Griffin, 1899
  - Birnie-Philip, Rosaline. ANS and ALS, 110 Rue du Bac, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bithell, Jethro. ALS, London, 1910 Jun 6 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bruan, Thomas (?). ALS, 1931 Dec 14 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Canfield, Richard. ALS, Paris, 1903 Apr 29 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Clarke, Isabelle H. ALS, Tytherington, Macclesfield, Cheshire, 1923 Sep 23 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Cole, Ashley T. ANS, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Scope and Contents
    In third person.
  - Crawford, Mrs. Virginia Mary (Smith). ALS, 3 E. Hyde Park Mansions, N.W. [London], Mar 31 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Dodwell, H Bruce. 2 ALS, Hampton Hill, Middlesex, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Edwards, Osman. ALS, London, 1900 Jun 24 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Grantoff, Otto. ALS, 11 Quai de Bourbon, Paris VI, [19]09 Apr 25 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Gray, John. ALS, 62 Chancery Lane, London (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Groom, Mrs. Gladys Laurence. 2 ALS, [19]26, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Hayden, Horace Edwin. ALS, Wilkes-Barre, Pa. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Hirschfeld, C. ALS and APS, Berlin-Charlottenberg 4, 1926, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Holman, Frank. ALS, Paris, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Hovey, Richard. ALS, 127 Rue de Ranalagh, [1896 Jul 6] (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Lawton, Frederick. ALS, 30 Rue Raynonard, Passy, 1905 Dec 7 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - McLaren, Malcolm S. ALS, Burford, Oxford, 1926 May 25 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Mertens, Eva? 2 ALS, Heidelberg, Grabengasse 16, 1927, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Mowrer, Edgar Ansel. ALS, Paris, 1914 Jul 27 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Nottingham, Cherry. ALS, Norfolk, Va., 1925 Nov 9 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Oldmeadow, Ernest James. 4 ALS, London, 1897-98 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - O'Neill, John. ALS, England, 1893 Feb 25 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Prince, Charles Albert. 7 ALS and APS, 1896-1905 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Prince, Helen Choate. 2 ALS, 1898, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Undated letter to Francis Marion Crawford introduces Vielé-Griffin.
  - Rudmose-Brown, Thomas Brown. 3 ALS, 1902, 1926, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Shepard, Jesse Francis. 2 ALS, [1892?], n.d. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Stanton, Theodore. 2 ALS, Paris, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Steiger, Isabel de. ALS, London, Sep 18 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Sturges, Jonathan. 3 ALS, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Tilton, Theodore. 2 ALS, Paris, 1893, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Tuckerman, Charles Keating. ALS, 1888 Sep 6 (Box 1, Folder 32)